<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Steefan Contractor</title>
    <link>https://steefancontractor.github.io/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Steefan Contractor</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2018</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +1100</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://steefancontractor.github.io/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Industry Resume</title>
      <link>https://steefancontractor.github.io/post/industry_cv/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Jul 2018 11:28:31 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://steefancontractor.github.io/post/industry_cv/</guid>
      <description>I have applied for The Data Incubator Fellowship program, a highly competitive fellowship aimed at bringing researchers with exceptional data analysis and statistical talent into industry. During the process I have been asked to update my resume based on some very helpful tips. I wish to share this advice with any fellow researchers interested in applying for industry data science positions. Note that I do NOT own any of the following information and The Data Incubator is completely within its rights to request me to take this post down, should they desire.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ARCCSS/CLEX Winter School 2018: Event Detection and Attribution</title>
      <link>https://steefancontractor.github.io/post/arccss-clex_winterschool_2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Jul 2018 19:20:25 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://steefancontractor.github.io/post/arccss-clex_winterschool_2018/</guid>
      <description>I attended the ARCCSS/CLEX winter school from 25th-29th June 2018. The theme of the winter school was climate extremes and so it involved lectures in the morning on various climate extremes (such as heatwaves and rainfall extremes) and also a group activity in the afternoons. The groups were tasked with producing analysis investigating one of five complex questions which are listed below.
 Project A: Examine the influence of modes of climate variability on temperature extremes over Australia Project B: Examine the influence of modes of climate variability on precipitation extremes over Australia Project C: Examine the role of soil moisture preconditioning on the frequency and/or intensity of heatwaves Project D: Examine changes in drought and what this means for impacts in Australia Project E: Pick a recent extreme event.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ResBaz 2018 - Visualising data on the web with D3</title>
      <link>https://steefancontractor.github.io/post/d3_softwarecarpentry_resbaz2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Jul 2018 06:07:57 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://steefancontractor.github.io/post/d3_softwarecarpentry_resbaz2018/</guid>
      <description>I created the above web based visualisation during a workshop on D3.js at ResBaz 2018. Here, you can read about my ResBaz experience and learn about how you can create a scatterplot like this too!
ResBaz 2018 On 4th July I participated in ResBaz 2018, an excellent conference for building and sharing research skills as well as networking. It is a fantastic platform for cross-disciplinary information and skill exchange.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Voting In The Senate</title>
      <link>https://steefancontractor.github.io/post/voting-in-the-senate/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Jul 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://steefancontractor.github.io/post/voting-in-the-senate/</guid>
      <description>The changed senate voting system actually makes a big difference to how we should vote this time around. In this blog I describe these changes and what they mean for us.
In the federal election we get to cast two votes, one for the local candidate in the House of Representatives and the other for the Senate Candidate. I am in the electorate of Grayndler which historically has been a very safe Labor seat and even though there is a lot of hype out there about the new Greens candidate Jim Cassey, I still think Albanese is going to safely keep his seat (I would love to be wrong).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bellbird Wall, Close Call</title>
      <link>https://steefancontractor.github.io/post/bellbird-wall-close-call/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Mar 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://steefancontractor.github.io/post/bellbird-wall-close-call/</guid>
      <description>Last Saturday, on 26th March 2016, a friend and fellow climber was injured while attempting a multipitch route near pulpit rock in Blackheath. This is a personal account of the events that unfolded.
The plan was to leave Sydney at 7am, bright and early, and do either some multipitching or canyoning. We could have done one of the Bowens Ck South canyons or Butterbox canyon or either Whymper or Bellbird wall multipitch routes.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>